



ALESSANDRO RONCONE

CURRICULUM VITAE I AM A ROBOTICS ENGINEER AND A DESIGNER



- Personal Website: (http://alecive.github.io)
- WHO AM I
- SUMMARY

Alessandro Roncone was born in Genova (GE), Italy, 1987. He received his *Bachelor's Degree* in *Biomedical Engineering* with the score of **110/110** with honors at the University of Genova in February 2008. In July 2011 he completed his *Master Degree in NeuroEngineering* (with the score of **110/110** with honors) in the same University. He is currently a *Ph.D. fellow at iCub Facility, Istituto Italiano di Tecnologia, GENOVA, Italy.* The goal of his Ph.D. project is to exploit insights from neuroscience in order to implement a model of *Peripersonal Space (PPS)* on the iCub. The PPS is thought to have a crucial role in humans as well as in animals, acting as an interface between the body and the outside world. It is defined as the space immediately surrounding our bodies, within which objects can be reached and manipulated. It is intimately multisensory, and shows high plasticity: it can be dynamically modulated by incoming information, short term or long term experience, and contextual demands.

EDUCATION

2012 - Present

ISTITUTO ITALIANO DI TECNOLOGIA (IIT), GENOVA IT PH.D. STUDENT

Life and Humanoid Technologies

Doctoral course in Robotics, Cognition and Interaction Technologies

2008 - 2011

UNIVERSITÀ DEGLI STUDI DI GENOVA, IT M.SC. WITH HONORS

Master Degree in NeuroEngineering

Thesis title 'Visuo-Haptic Integration for Object Characterization in an Unstructured Environment'

2005 - 2008

UNIVERSITÀ DEGLI STUDI DI GENOVA, IT B.SC. WITH HONORS

Bachelor Degree in Biomedical Engineering

Thesis title `Support Vector Machine Analysis applied to a Manipulator in a NonStructured Environment`

2005 - 2008

UNIVERSITÀ DEGLI STUDI DI GENOVA, IT STUDENT WITH SCOLARSHIP AT ISICT

c/o Istituto Superiore di Studi in Tecnologie dell'Informazione e della Comunicazione

PUBLICATIONS

2014

IEEE-RAS International Conference On Humanoid Robots

Madrid, Spain, November 18-20, 2014

GAZE STABILIZATION FOR HUMANOID ROBOTS: A COMPREHENSIVE FRAMEWORK

Alessandro Roncone, Ugo Pattacini, Giorgio Metta, and Lorenzo Natale

2014

IEEE-RAS International Conference On Humanoid Robots

Madrid, Spain, November 18-20, 2014

3D STEREO ESTIMATION AND FULLY AUTOMATED LEARNING OF EYE-HAND COORDINATION IN HUMANOID ROBOTS

S. R. Fanello, U. Pattacini, I. Gori, V. Tikhanoff, M. Randazzo, A. Roncone, F. Odone, and G. Metta

2014

IEEE International Conference On Robotics And Automation (ICRA)

Hong Kong, China, May 31-June 7, 2014

AUTOMATIC KINEMATIC CHAIN CALIBRATION USING ARTIFICIAL SKIN: SELF-TOUCH IN THE ICUB HUMANOID ROBOT

Alessandro Roncone, Matej Hoffmann, Ugo Pattacini, and Giorgio Metta

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2012 - Present

Istituto Italiano Di Tecnologia (IIT), Genova IT

PH.D. FELLOW

Life and Humanoid Technologies

Doctoral course in Robotics, Cognition and Interaction Technologies

Jul. - Oct. 2013

Coop La Lucerna

ICON DESIGNER

Icon Designer in outsourcing

Oct. - Dec. 2011 Magor Corp. ICON DESIGNER

Icon Designer in outsourcing

Feb. - Mar. 2013
The Castle Project
ICON DESIGNER

Icon Designer in outsourcing

GRAPHIC DESIGN

2013 - Present FLATWOKEN ICONS

2010 - 2013 AWOKEN ICONS

SKILLS AND TECHNICAL EXPERTISE

Programming Skills:

C++ MATLAB CSS3 & HTML5 BASH R PYTHON

CM Skills:

GIT SUBVERSION

Mobile Skills:

ANDROID

Software Skills:

LINUX WINDOWS GIMP INKSCAPE

Languages:

ITALIAN ENGLISH FRENCH

This CV has been auto(-magically) generated from the correspondent page on my personal website. For this reason, there may be some formatting problems here and there. Compilation Date: *October 24, 2014*